<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>sofiainjp</title>
    <link href="https://sofiainjp.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://sofiainjp.com" />
    <updated>2022-08-05T09:01:34+09:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Sofia</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://sofiainjp.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Startup in Japan-Furniture &amp; Phone number</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sofiainjp.com/startup-furniture-and-phone-number.html"/>
        <id>https://sofiainjp.com/startup-furniture-and-phone-number.html</id>
            <category term="Startup in Japan"/>

        <updated>2022-08-05T08:57:27+09:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/26/5.jpg" alt="" />
                    Shopping for furniture in Japan is a great thing to do, there are so many new products available but also so many brands and new products that it can be confusing at times! Here is a guide to where you can buy furniture and appliances,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/26/5.jpg" alt="" />
                <div class="cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x c1et5uql o9v6fnle ii04i59q">
<div dir="auto">Shopping for furniture in Japan is a great thing to do, there are so many new products available but also so many brands and new products that it can be confusing at times! Here is a guide to where you can buy furniture and appliances, and how to apply for a mobile phone number and internet access.</div>
<div dir="auto"> </div>
<div dir="auto">Home appliance purchase locations: yodobashi, big camera, Yamada denki</div>
<div dir="auto"> </div>
<div dir="auto">In Taiwan, buyers of home appliances may go to places such as Chan Kun, National Electronics, Tatung Home Appliances, etc. to learn about the new products of various brands. In Japan, you can go to yodobashi, big camera and Yamada denki, where many of the latest appliances are on display with illustrations and descriptions, making it easy to shop even if your Japanese is not good enough. Also, during the peak moving season from March to May, there are complete sets of appliances available for sale at lower prices.</div>
<div dir="auto">    You can compare the prices of the same products in different shopping malls and consider the rebate points. For example, yodobashi and big camera have rebate points and one point is usually discounted to one dollar, which is a good deal. You can use your points to buy small appliances or other items after you have bought the higher priced appliances first. In addition, points can be used to offset the cost of extended warranties, giving you more peace of mind overall. </div>
<div dir="auto">    Also, when you buy a number of large appliances at once, you can usually get a discount on the price! If your Japanese is not good enough, you can ask for help from a Chinese speaking staff or use translation software to help you communicate with them. In general, the language itself doesn't affect the quality of the service you receive from the shop. The discounts offered at large stores are not very different and finding a staff member or shop that you feel comfortable interacting with will improve your shopping mood!</div>
<div dir="auto"> </div>
<div dir="auto"> </div>
<div dir="auto">Furniture shopping locations: Idli, MUJI, IKEA, Rakuten Market</div>
<div dir="auto"> </div>
<div dir="auto">If you want to buy sofas, TV cabinets, dining tables and chairs, bed frames, etc. in Japan, you can basically do it all at<strong> </strong>Nitori. You just need to have a good idea of the size of the item you need, go to Nitori or MUJI to confirm the item and then place your order directly with the shop staff, but buying furniture is different from buying electricity, as the price is usually the total amount of the purchase and there are no additional discounts. Even so, the quality of the products and service is really good. When they are delivered to your home, they are carried carefully to avoid hitting the doors or walls, and afterwards they will help you to install them and put them in the designated place.When assembling, the flooring is mostly covered with mats to avoid scratching the wood.<br><br></div>
<div dir="auto">Tip :</div>
<ol>
<li dir="auto">When buying a fridge or washing machine, it is important to pay attention to the size and orientation of the door. It is advisable to check the size of your home and whether it is against a wall before purchasing the product.</li>
<li dir="auto">It is also important that the home has a lift and that the lift is large enough to accommodate the appliances and furniture purchased.</li>
<li dir="auto">Some items have an additional installation fee. Most appliances and furniture will be delivered and installed for you, but some will not be installed and there will be an additional charge if you need a service person to come and install them. However, this will be clearly explained to you at the time of purchase and there will be no unexplained charges.</li>
</ol>
<br>
<div dir="auto"> </div>
</div>
<div>Mobile phone number application: softbank, docomo, au, three major telecom solutions</div>
<div>Once you have obtained your resident card, you can start doing many things! For example: mobile phone numbers, bank accounts (usually only post office banks can be opened first), home internet, credit cards, other membership cards.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Once in Japan, it is advisable to apply for a Japanese phone number to save on international roaming charges and in many cases you will need a phone number in the future!</div>
<div>    In Taiwan, most people apply for the full plan, however, the cost of telecommunication in Japan is relatively high, so it is advisable to evaluate your monthly usage to decide on a plan. The three major telecoms in Japan have relatively cheap plans: docomo "ahamo", Softbank "LINEMO" and au "povo 2.0", all of which can be applied for online and are very convenient. I chose to apply for the LINEMO plan!<br><br></div>
<div>LINEMO uses Softbank backline and the quality is quite stable. There are two tariff plans, "Mini Plan ミニプラン (3GB per month JPY990円)" and "Smaho Plan スマホプラン (20GB per month JPY2,728円)". All plans are included in "LINE Giga Free".<br>This means that you can use LINE for unlimited messaging and internet calls without having your monthly traffic deducted, which is very convenient for people who use LINE a lot and don't have to worry about calling back to Taiwan or anywhere else. (LINE location sharing, LINE Live, LINE Sticker Store, news browsing, etc. are not included in the free internet traffic) </div>
<div> </div>
<div>Documents required for application：</div>
<ol>
<li>Personal identification documents: resident card and passport. If you enter a name or address different from the one on your confirmation card, you will need to upload supplementary information.</li>
<li>Payment method (credit card in your name or account in Japan). You can apply with a Taiwanese credit card!</li>
<li>E-mail address to receive confirmation immediately</li>
<li>Mobile phones without SIM lock</li>
</ol>
<p><a href="https://www.linemo.jp/process/">You can find a detailed explanation of the process on the official website</a>. After the screening process, your application for a Japan Linemo SIM card will be sent directly to your home. A resident card is really important!<br><br>--To be continued</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Startup  in Japan-Rent an apartment</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sofiainjp.com/rent-an-apartment.html"/>
        <id>https://sofiainjp.com/rent-an-apartment.html</id>
            <category term="Startup in Japan"/>

        <updated>2022-08-05T09:01:34+09:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/25/4.jpg" alt="" />
                    If you get a start-up visa and enter Japan successfully, the first difficulty you will encounter is renting an apartment. It is not easy to find a suitable room in Japan. It is advisable to rent a suite for a month when you first arrive&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/25/4.jpg" alt="" />
                <div class="post__entry u-inner">
<p>If you get a start-up visa and enter Japan successfully, the first difficulty you will encounter is renting an apartment. It is not easy to find a suitable room in Japan. It is advisable to rent a suite for a month when you first arrive in Japan because you will need to apply for a resident card at the ward office two weeks after entering Japan (Remember! After you have processed your resident card, your health insurance card and pension payment will be sent to this address. If you change your address, remember to go to the ward office and post office as soon as possible to correct your address). So, in addition to having an address to log into your resident card, you can also find your ideal place to live during this time! Of course, if you don't mind sharing a bathroom, a share house is also an option. Many share houses are willing to allow renters to register their resident card. By the way! Hotel and Airbnb addresses cannot be used as a resident card address, so don't forget!</p>
<p><strong>"The Resident Card" is a very important document to prove that you are staying in Japan and must be applied for at the ward office within two weeks of your arrival.</strong> It is also an important document if you wish to apply for a mobile phone number in Japan.</p>
<p>Why is it not easy to rent an apartment in Japan?</p>
<ol>
<li>You usually need to find an agent to rent an apartment in Japan, and because of the language, the choices are limited. But don't forget to look for a few agents. A good agent will look out for you and help you get the right property, rather than asking you to make compromises. In the past, many Chinese bought houses in Japan and rented them out. Some of the properties they rented out were not in good condition and the prices were high, because they knew that the difficulties of foreigners were poor in Japanese and that it was difficult to rent a house, so they were able to rent out even the worst properties. Although the initial conditions for foreigners looking to rent an apartment are inherently poor, there is always a chance of finding a good agent if you have the opportunity to find a few more. After all, the initial cost of renting an apartment in Japan is high and so is the cost of moving, so if you can spend a little more time and effort looking for the right one at the beginning, you will be able to spend less money.</li>
<li>A guarantor is usually required to rent an apartment in Japan, and it is often preferable for this guarantor to be of Japanese nationality. Most foreigners do not have a guarantor, so when choosing a property to rent, it is usually necessary to consider whether the property is guaranteed by a guarantor company, which of course requires an additional fee.</li>
<li>It's also harder to find suitable accommodation if you have pets! There are many buildings where pets are not allowed by convention, I guess for fear of "causing disturbance to neighbours". When renting an apartment in Japan, it is very important not to disturb or affect the neighbours, after all it is a communal living environment. In Taiwan, although the management committee keeps an eye on it every day, not everyone is able to do so, but in Japan, although there is no management committee, everyone does their best to maintain the quality of living and not to cause disturbance to others.</li>
</ol>
<p>Is the living space in Japan small? It depends on your lifestyle. If you have a lot of clutter, you may have to choose a larger space, but the rents in metropolitan areas are relatively high, so you may have to strike a balance between living space and rent!</p>
<p>Can you only rent empty houses in Japan? Most of the rental properties in Japan are empty, although some are air-conditioned, but most of them are rented out as empty properties. I guess it is probably because "not to cause distress to others", if the rented property contains furniture or household appliances, but the new tenant wants to buy a new sofa, refrigerator or has these appliances or furniture themselves, then the new tenant has to pay to get rid of these items first.<br>In view of the potential distress caused to the new renter, it is common in Japan to rent accommodation on a vacant basis.Once you have rented an apartment in Japan, you will need to go to the market to buy the appliances and items you need, and of course there are many second-hand furniture sales where you can find the right things. Finally, once you have rented the property, you will need to get the water, electricity and gas connected to the property. If you find a good housing agent, this will be much easier!</p>
<p><br>As for rent payment, in Japan, it is usually paid by automatic bank deduction, but in order to open a bank account, you need to have a place to live. This was a problem at first, but we could ask our agent to help us coordinate, for example, if we could pay a few months' rent in cash and wait for the bank account to be opened before switching to automatic deduction.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I am grateful when I meet good people or receive help from others when I live abroad!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>These are the things that come to mind for the time being for the rental section, but I will leave the rest for another time.<br><br>--To be continued</p>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Startup  in Japan-Start Up Visa</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sofiainjp.com/start-up-visa.html"/>
        <id>https://sofiainjp.com/start-up-visa.html</id>
            <category term="Startup in Japan"/>

        <updated>2022-08-05T08:51:31+09:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/24/3.jpg" alt="" />
                    With regard to the application for a management visa, hiring an administrative clerk is a way to simplify the process a lot, but remember to find an administrative clerk you can trust! In addition to discussing your business management plan with the administrative clerk, the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/24/3.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>With regard to the application for a management visa, hiring an administrative clerk is a way to simplify the process a lot, but remember to find an administrative clerk you can trust! In addition to discussing your business management plan with the administrative clerk, the administrative clerk will also give you feedback and suggestions to complete your plan, followed by remittance of funds into Japan, but it is not easy to remit funds into Japan!</p>
<p>In my shallow understanding, your company should first have a Japanese partner and use his name to open a company, bank account, rent an office, as for the details may have to ask the administrative clerk, after all, this is their professional services, find a professional and experienced administrative clerk to discuss, not only in the preparation of documents to give advice, but also to help determine whether the business plan is feasible, a long-term business plan is the prerequisite for everything.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Setting up the company itself is not difficult, but whether or not it can continue to operate smoothly is the real difficulty.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In addition to asking professional administrative clerks to help you apply for a business management visa, there is another type of program called a "business start-up visa". Some local governments have established a support program for foreign entrepreneurs to manage their business activities, and the Ministry of Economy, Trade and Industry (METI) has approved this program, which aims to expand the number of foreign entrepreneurs and promote the development of entrepreneurship.</p>
<p>When applying for a visa to start a business, foreign entrepreneurs who wish to start a business submit a "Business Preparation Activity Plan", etc. to the local government organization listed below. The local government organization will determine whether the necessary requirements for a visa are met and issue a certificate of confirmation to the foreign entrepreneur. If the foreign entrepreneur submits a certificate of confirmation issued by the local government and the necessary documents to the local immigration office, the foreign entrepreneur will be granted a residence permit for a maximum of one year (to be renewed after six months) for "specified activities" if the result of the examination determines that the requirements are met, and the foreign entrepreneur will be able to prepare for starting a business. After entering Japan and meeting the requirements for the "Management" status of residence during the period of stay, the foreign company may change its status of residence to "Management" and actually start a business in Japan.</p>
<p>If you have a 6-month "Start-up Visa", you can set up a company after you arrive in Japan. In many places in Japan, there are autonomous organizations that promote foreign entrepreneurial talents, so please refer to the website of the Ministry of Economy, Trade and Industry's Foreign Entrepreneurial Activities Promotion Program. For example, Tokyo is inclined to entrepreneurial projects such as "urban regeneration, medical treatment, entrepreneurship, employment, promotion of women's activism, etc." and Niigata City also encourages foreigners to start their own businesses there. If you are interested, you can learn more.</p>
<p>Through the "Start-up Visa", you have the opportunity to start a business in Japan even if you do not have a partner in Japan, that is, by submitting the required information to the local government (in the case of Niigata City)</p>
<ol>
<li>Application for Confirmation of Business Startup Activities</li>
<li>Plan for Business Startup Activities</li>
<li>Time Schedule of Business Startup Activities</li>
<li>Resume of the applicant</li>
<li>Written Pledge</li>
<li>Documents clarifying where the applicant will be residing for 6 months after arrival in Japan</li>
<li>Documents detailing the applicant's bank account balance</li>
<li>A copy of the applicant's passport (the page showing the identification details)</li>
<li>Other necessary documents</li>
</ol>
<p>The local government can provide consultation services in English, we can further understand the information we need to submit through email, so that we can be more perfect preparation, when the information is submitted, the local Japanese personnel will further understand your business through your business plan, the future operation mode, and examine your business model, if there is no problem after examination, the Japanese side will issue a "Certificate of Eligibility", and when this certificate is obtained and means you can enter Japan to formally establish a company.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The most difficult first step is to obtain a "Certificate of Eligibility".</p>
</blockquote>
<p>After the first step, the next is to continue to walk ~<br><br>--Continued</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Startup  in Japan-Company establishment</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sofiainjp.com/company-establishment.html"/>
        <id>https://sofiainjp.com/company-establishment.html</id>
            <category term="Startup in Japan"/>

        <updated>2022-08-05T08:46:45+09:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/23/1.jpg" alt="" />
                    If you want to stay in Japan for more than three months, the most important thing is the "visa". In 2005, the Japanese government enacted regulations to facilitate foreign businessmen to stay in Japan for a long period of time, the so-called "investment and management&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/23/1.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>If you want to stay in Japan for more than three months, the most important thing is the "visa". In 2005, the Japanese government enacted regulations to facilitate foreign businessmen to stay in Japan for a long period of time, the so-called "investment and management visa", and under the Abe regime, further relaxed the restrictions on foreigners starting a business in Japan and renamed the "investment and management visa" to the current "management visa". The "business management visa" is a visa for mid- to long-term stay in Japan that can be applied for by establishing a company in Japan and carrying out business and management activities.</p>
<p><br>When I was still in Taiwan, I started to search for information on the Internet and learn about the requirements for applying for a business management visa. The following is a summary of the information I found.</p>
<ol>
<li>Company size: The new company must invest at least 5 million yen or employ two or more full-time employees. Most people choose to invest at least 5 million yen (the minimum amount) because they have to pay the monthly salary as well as the social benefits (annuity, insurance, etc.) of the employees. The important thing is that the person applying for a business management visa must be doing "business management work".</li>
<li>Business plan: When applying for a visa, you must submit a business plan to the Immigration Bureau, detailing your company's business content and development direction, and more importantly, you must convince the Japanese government that the business plan is feasible and sustainable, i.e., that you have a long-term business plan and a viable business model.</li>
<li>Office requirements: a physical office, a shared office or a rented office address or a virtual office is not acceptable.</li>
<li>Operating right requirement: Applicant must own the actual operating right of the company.</li>
</ol>
<p>The "Business Management Visa" expects the applicant to have substantial business management activities and to be able to run a stable business for a long time, bringing tax revenue and employment opportunities to the Japanese society. Many rich people think that if they buy a house in Japan and collect rent as an investment, they can get a business management visa and further immigrate to Japan, but the truth is that if they only buy real estate and collect rent as an investment, then they are not involved in business management and are not eligible for a business management visa.</p>
<p>All of the above is the information available on the Internet. But what is the actual situation?</p>
<p>First of all, the company's scale of operation, although it is mentioned in the information that a capital of 5 million yen is fine, but in reality, it is necessary to consider whether you want to come alone or with your family, of course, the higher the capital is the better, after all, it is not as easy as you think to live in Japan, there are many taxes and insurance materials to pay!</p>
<p>Then there is the business plan, which is a good plan and review of your future business, completed in Chinese and then translated into Japanese with the help of a professional translator. Don't think of it as a mere report. This plan is actually an important basis to help you understand whether your business can survive in Japan.What are all the costs of setting up a business (office rental, internet, utilities, phone, hiring professional staff, cost of products, etc.), and can the income be generated without a deficit? These are all things that a business plan can help you understand. Of course, you can also pay an executive clerk to help you, but you still have to plan it yourself first to get a better idea of the details, right? After all, if you want to be the boss of a company in the future, you can't be unaware of the company's finances and vision!</p>
<p>How do I rent an office? How do I send money to Japan? This chicken begets the egg begets the chicken question .....<br><br>--Continued</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Before Start up  in Japan</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sofiainjp.com/before-start-up.html"/>
        <id>https://sofiainjp.com/before-start-up.html</id>
            <category term="Startup in Japan"/>

        <updated>2022-08-05T08:47:32+09:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/22/travel-2-2xl.jpeg" alt="" />
                    Many people like to travel to Japan. For Taiwanese, the frequency of visiting Japan may be once, twice or more a year, but have you ever thought about living in Japan? I love Japan so much that I often arrange time to see cherry blossoms&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/22/travel-2-2xl.jpeg" alt="" />
                <p>Many people like to travel to Japan. For Taiwanese, the frequency of visiting Japan may be once, twice or more a year, but have you ever thought about living in Japan?</p>
<p>I love Japan so much that I often arrange time to see cherry blossoms and maples in Japan during my busy work schedule.</p>
<p>I had imagined that I would live in Japan instead of just traveling, enjoying and experiencing the local life, and feeling the change of seasons, but in reality, it was almost a "dream or fantasy". I never thought that I could really move to Japan in 2022, before the global epidemic has completely subsided.</p>
<p>The most common ways to live in Japan for more than three months are to seek a job in Japan or to marry a Japanese person. If you are still young and have some savings, you can first go to a Japanese language school to improve your language skills and make friends, and then consider finding a job in Japan. Both of these options seem to be suitable for young people.</p>
<p>I am not young anymore, so we choose to start a business in Japan.</p>
<p>It is not easy to start a business in Japan. First, imagine what you have to give up. It may be a stable and respectable job, a sheltered house, a car, and many other physical or abstract things. After thinking about what you might need to let go of and accepting the reality of opportunity costs, then start thinking about how to live in Japan, or to put it plainly, how to make a living.</p>
<p>It's easy to travel to Japan when you enjoy your vacation because you only need to pay for it with your salary. However, if you want to live in Japan, having savings can really help you survive, but having savings alone will not allow you to live in Japan for a long time because the most important thing is the "visa" (work visa, family stay visa, business management visa, etc.). Can you really make money? The above two items are still slightly under your control, but there are many, many things that you cannot control in the future.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>After experiencing the idea that "many things are beyond my control", I seem to be able to "appreciate every opportunity and encounter" and live a more grateful and appreciative life.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>How do I start a business in Japan? How do I start in a foreign country?<br><br>--To be continued</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>日本創業-傢俱&amp;手機門號</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sofiainjp.com/ri-ben-chuang-ye-jia-juandshou-ji-men-haofurniture-and-phone-number.html"/>
        <id>https://sofiainjp.com/ri-ben-chuang-ye-jia-juandshou-ji-men-haofurniture-and-phone-number.html</id>
            <category term="Startup in Japan"/>

        <updated>2022-08-05T08:57:13+09:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/21/5.jpg" alt="" />
                    在日本採購家具是一件很棒的事情，有許多最新的商品，但也因為太多廠牌、太多新產品而有時會眼花撩亂啊！下面就介紹一下可以到哪裡採購家電、家俱以及可以如何申辦手機門號及網路。 家電採購地點：yodobashi 、big camera、Yamada denki 在台灣買家電可能會去燦坤、全國電子、大同家電等等地方了解各品牌，在日本則可以到yodobashi 、big camera、Yamada denki 這三間商場選購，許多最新的家電都會在店內展示並有圖文並茂的介紹，即便日文不夠好都能夠輕鬆的選購，此外，當遇到3-5月搬家旺季時，也會有成套的家電一起販售、價格也會較為便宜。同樣的產品在不同的商場也會有不同的價格，可以多比價一下，另外可以考慮回饋點數，像是yodobashi 、big camera都會有回饋點數且一點通常可以折抵一元，其實非常划算，可以先買單價高的電器後，再用點數來購買小電器或其他商品，此外，點數也能作為延長保固的折抵費用，整體而言，可以讓你買得更安心一點。另外，當一次購買多樣大型家電，通常價格都能再享優惠！如果日文不夠好，可以找會說華語的服務人員協助，或是可以透過翻譯軟體來幫助自己與對方溝通，整體而言，語言本身並不會影響店家的服務品質。而大型賣場的優惠不會差非常多，找到一個讓你感覺互動舒適的服務人員或店家，會提升採購的心情！ 家俱採購地點：宜得利、無印良品、IKEA、楽天市場 在日本如果要採購沙發、電視櫃、餐桌椅、床架等，基本上在宜得利就可以完整的選購完畢，只要把需要的商品尺寸良好，到宜得利或無印良品確認商品後就可直接向店員下單，但買家俱跟買家電不同，通常價格就是選購的總額、沒有額外優惠。即便如此，商品及服務品質真的很棒，送到家中時，會小心的搬運、避免撞到門或牆壁，之後也後會協助安裝、擺放到指定位置，且在組裝時會避免刮傷木頭地板，多半會鋪著地墊。 小提醒： 手機門號申辦：softbank、docomo、au、三大電信格安方案 至於詳細流程，可以到官網上有清楚的圖文解說！審査完畢後，申請的日本LINEMO SIM卡(網卡・電話卡)會直接寄到家中。在留卡真的很重要啊！！ --未完待續
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/21/5.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>在日本採購家具是一件很棒的事情，有許多最新的商品，但也因為太多廠牌、太多新產品而有時會眼花撩亂啊！下面就介紹一下可以到哪裡採購家電、家俱以及可以如何申辦手機門號及網路。</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #000000; text-decoration: underline;">家電採購地點：yodobashi 、big camera、Yamada denki</span></span></p>
<p>在台灣買家電可能會去燦坤、全國電子、大同家電等等地方了解各品牌，在日本則可以到yodobashi 、big camera、Yamada denki 這三間商場選購，許多最新的家電都會在店內展示並有圖文並茂的介紹，即便日文不夠好都能夠輕鬆的選購，此外，當遇到3-5月搬家旺季時，也會有成套的家電一起販售、價格也會較為便宜。同樣的產品在不同的商場也會有不同的價格，可以多比價一下，另外可以考慮回饋點數，像是yodobashi 、big camera都會有回饋點數且一點通常可以折抵一元，其實非常划算，可以先買單價高的電器後，再用點數來購買小電器或其他商品，此外，點數也能作為延長保固的折抵費用，整體而言，可以讓你買得更安心一點。另外，當一次購買多樣大型家電，通常價格都能再享優惠！如果日文不夠好，可以找會說華語的服務人員協助，或是可以透過翻譯軟體來幫助自己與對方溝通，整體而言，語言本身並不會影響店家的服務品質。而大型賣場的優惠不會差非常多，找到一個讓你感覺互動舒適的服務人員或店家，會提升採購的心情！</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #000000; text-decoration: underline;">家俱採購地點：宜得利、無印良品、IKEA、楽天市場</span></span></p>
<p>在日本如果要採購沙發、電視櫃、餐桌椅、床架等，基本上在宜得利就可以完整的選購完畢，只要把需要的商品尺寸良好，到宜得利或無印良品確認商品後就可直接向店員下單，但買家俱跟買家電不同，通常價格就是選購的總額、沒有額外優惠。即便如此，商品及服務品質真的很棒，送到家中時，會小心的搬運、避免撞到門或牆壁，之後也後會協助安裝、擺放到指定位置，且在組裝時會避免刮傷木頭地板，多半會鋪著地墊。</p>
<p>小提醒：</p>
<ol>
<li>在採買冰箱、洗衣機的時候一定要注意尺寸還有開門的方向，建議先確認住家的尺寸及是否靠牆等再來選購商品。</li>
<li>住家是否有電梯、電梯尺寸是否能容納採購的家電及傢俱也非常重要，如果無法放入電梯而需要人工搬運，就會收取額外的運送費用。</li>
<li>有些商品會有額外的安裝費用。大多數的家電及傢俱都是會幫你送到並幫你安裝好，但有些則不協助安裝，如果要服務人員到家安裝則要另外收費。但這些在採購的時候，店員都會清楚說明、不會有不明不白的費用產生。</li>
</ol>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">手機門號申辦：softbank、docomo、au、三大電信格安方案</span></p>
<div class="cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x c1et5uql o9v6fnle ii04i59q">
<div dir="auto">當獲得「在留卡」後就可以開始辦理很多事情！例如：<span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">手機門號、</span><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">銀行戶頭(通常只能先開郵局銀行)、家用網路、信用卡、其他會員卡。</span></div>
<div dir="auto"> </div>
<div dir="auto">到日本後建議直接辦理日本門號，節省國際漫遊費且未來在很多情況下都會需要電話號碼！在台灣時多數人會辦理吃到飽方案，然而，日本的電信費相對高，建議評估自己每個月的使用量來決定方案。日本的三大電信都有出相對較便宜的方案，docomo「ahamo」、Softbank「 LINEMO」、au「povo 2.0」，均可以線上申請、非常方便。我選擇申請LINEMO方案！</div>
</div>
<div> </div>
<div class="cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x c1et5uql o9v6fnle ii04i59q">LINEMO使用的是Softbank回線，品質滿穩定的。有兩種資費方案，「Mini Plan ミニプラン（3GB　每個月日幣990円）」以及「Smaho Plan スマホプラン（20GB　每個月日幣2,728円）」。所有的資費方案都導入「LINE Giga Free」，也就是不計算LINE用掉的網路流量，也就是可無限使用LINE來傳訊息、打網路電話而不會扣掉每月的流量，對於常用line聯繫的人非常的方便，打回台灣或其他各地都不用擔心。（LINE定位分享、LINE直播、LINE貼圖商店、瀏覽新聞等不包含在免費網路流量內）。<br>
<div dir="auto"> </div>
</div>
<div>申辦所需的文件：</div>
<ol>
<li>本人確認證件：在留卡＆護照。若輸入的姓名、地址與本人確認證件上記載的不同，需要上傳輔助資料。</li>
<li>支付方式（本人名義信用卡or在日帳戶）。使用台灣信用卡也能成功申請！</li>
<li>可馬上收信確認的電子郵件信箱e-mail</li>
<li>沒有鎖SIM的手機</li>
</ol>
<p>至於詳細流程，可以到<a href="https://www.linemo.jp/process/">官網上有清楚的圖文解說</a>！審査完畢後，申請的日本LINEMO SIM卡(網卡・電話卡)會直接寄到家中。在留卡真的很重要啊！！</p>
<p>--未完待續</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>日本創業-租房</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sofiainjp.com/ri-ben-chuang-ye-2.html"/>
        <id>https://sofiainjp.com/ri-ben-chuang-ye-2.html</id>
            <category term="Startup in Japan"/>

        <updated>2022-08-05T08:55:03+09:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/20/4.jpg" alt="" />
                    如果你拿到了創業簽證並順利進入日本，第一個會遇到的困難就是租房子。在日本租到適合的房間並不容易，建議剛到日本時可以先租「日租套房」約一個月，因為入境後的兩週需要到區役所去申辦「在留卡」，在留卡中需要登記你目前在日本居住的地址（記得！辦理完在留卡後，就會有健保証、年金繳交等等送至這個地址，建議盡可能先租一個月左右，若改地址也要記得盡快到區役所還有郵局更正地址！），因此，租借「日租套房」除了有地址可以登入「在留卡」外，也能在這段時間找尋心中理想的居住地點！當然，如果你不介意與他人共用衛浴的話，share house也是一個選擇，有許多share house是願意讓租借者登入在留卡的，建議可以先寫信詢問是否能登記在留卡的住址。對了！飯店以及Airbnb的地址不能作為在留卡地址登記使用，千萬別忘了！ 「在留卡」是一個很重要的證件，是你在日本滯留的身份證明，到日本兩週內一定要去區役所辦理！此外，若希望在日本申辦手機門號，在留卡也是很重要的證件呢！ 為何在日本租房不容易？ 日本的居住空間都偏小？這可能要看每個人的生活習慣了，如果本身雜物就是比較多的人， 可能就要選比較大的空間居住，但是都會區的租金相對高，可能就要在生活空間和租金之間取得平衡了！ 日本只能租到空屋？大多的日本租屋物件都是空屋，雖有些會配有冷氣，但大多是以空屋出租為主，我猜想可能是因為「不要造成他人困擾」，如果租的房內含有家具或家電，但新租客想要購買新沙發、冰箱或本身就有這些家電或家具，那麼新租客必須要先花錢處理掉這些物品，考量到可能會造成新租客的困擾，日本通常以空房的方式出租房屋。因此，在日本租到房後，需要到賣場去選購需要的家電、物品，當然也有許多二手傢俱販售處可以找到合適的東西，這就要花時間去比價、了解。最後，租到房後要開通租屋處的水、電及瓦斯，這些都要聯絡相關單位，若你找到一個好的房屋仲介，這些事情就會簡單許多！ 至於房租繳納部分，日本通常是透過銀行自動扣繳為主，但要開立銀行帳戶又需要先有住處，這個雞生蛋、蛋生雞的問題一開始也非常困擾我們，但可以請房仲協助協調，譬如是否能先用現金繳納幾個月的費用，等待銀行帳戶開立後才轉換成自動扣繳等等。 在外地生活遇到好人或受到他人協助時，心中真的滿滿感激！ 租屋的部分暫時想到這些事情，至於其他則另開篇幅。 --未完待續
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/20/4.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>如果你拿到了創業簽證並順利進入日本，第一個會遇到的困難就是租房子。在日本租到適合的房間並不容易，建議剛到日本時可以先租「日租套房」約一個月，因為<span style="color: #843fa1;">入境後的<strong><span style="color: #e03e2d;">兩週</span></strong>需要到區役所去申辦「在留卡」，在留卡中需要登記你目前在日本居住的地址（<strong>記得！辦理完在留卡後，就會有健保証、年金繳交等等送至這個地址，建議盡可能先租一個月左右，若改地址也要記得盡快到區役所還有郵局更正地址！</strong>），</span>因此，租借「日租套房」除了有地址可以登入「在留卡」外，也能在這段時間找尋心中理想的居住地點！當然，如果你不介意與他人共用衛浴的話，share house也是一個選擇，有許多share house是願意讓租借者登入在留卡的，建議可以先寫信詢問是否能登記在留卡的住址。對了！飯店以及Airbnb的地址不能作為在留卡地址登記使用，千萬別忘了！</p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #e03e2d;">「在留卡」是一個很重要的證件，是你在日本滯留的身份證明，到日本兩週內一定要去區役所辦理！</span></strong>此外，若希望在日本申辦手機門號，在留卡也是很重要的證件呢！</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">為何在日本租房不容易？</span></p>
<ol>
<li>在日本租房通常需要透過房屋仲介，因為語言的關係，能選擇的本來就很有限，但別忘了要多找幾個房屋仲介，好的房屋仲介會處身為你設想、協助你租到合適的房，而不會要你將就、妥協。過去有很多華人在日本購屋並出租，有些出租物件本身的條件並不好、租金又高，因為他們知道外國人的痛點是日文差、難以租到房子，所以再差的物件都能租得出去。雖然外國人要租房的初期條件本身就很差，若有機會多找幾個房仲，總是有機會碰到好房仲、找到自己喜歡的物件。畢竟在日本租房的初期費用高、搬家的支出也高，若能在一開始多花點時間和精力尋找適合的，也能少花點冤枉錢。</li>
<li>在日本租房通常需要「保證人」，而這個「保證人」通常是日本籍的日本人為佳。大多數的外國人並沒有「保證人」，因此通常在選擇租房物件時，需要考量該物件是否有提供「保證公司」來作為擔保，當然，這是需要另外付額外的費用。</li>
<li>若有寵物也會比較難找到合適的物件！有許多大樓公約是不能養寵物，我猜是擔心「造成鄰居困擾」。在日本租房時，不打擾或影響鄰居是很重要的，畢竟這是公共生活環境，包含降低音量、在規定的時間倒垃圾、在夜間不要洗衣服等等，這些都是希望讓居住品質更好。在台灣，雖然管委會天天盯著，但並非人人都能做到，但在日本，雖沒有管委會，但大家都盡力的維護居住品質、不造成他人困擾。</li>
</ol>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">日本的居住空間都偏小？</span>這可能要看每個人的生活習慣了，如果本身雜物就是比較多的人， 可能就要選比較大的空間居住，但是都會區的租金相對高，可能就要在生活空間和租金之間取得平衡了！</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">日本只能租到空屋？</span>大多的日本租屋物件都是空屋，雖有些會配有冷氣，但大多是以空屋出租為主，我猜想可能是因為「不要造成他人困擾」，如果租的房內含有家具或家電，但新租客想要購買新沙發、冰箱或本身就有這些家電或家具，那麼新租客必須要先花錢處理掉這些物品，考量到可能會造成新租客的困擾，日本通常以空房的方式出租房屋。因此，在日本租到房後，需要到賣場去選購需要的家電、物品，當然也有許多二手傢俱販售處可以找到合適的東西，這就要花時間去比價、了解。最後，租到房後要開通租屋處的水、電及瓦斯，這些都要聯絡相關單位，若你找到一個好的房屋仲介，這些事情就會簡單許多！</p>
<p>至於<span style="text-decoration: underline;">房租繳納</span>部分，日本通常是透過銀行自動扣繳為主，但要開立銀行帳戶又需要先有住處，這個雞生蛋、蛋生雞的問題一開始也非常困擾我們，但可以請房仲協助協調，譬如是否能先用現金繳納幾個月的費用，等待銀行帳戶開立後才轉換成自動扣繳等等。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>在外地生活遇到好人或受到他人協助時，心中真的滿滿感激！</p>
</blockquote>
<p>租屋的部分暫時想到這些事情，至於其他則另開篇幅。</p>
<p>--未完待續</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>日本創業-簽證</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sofiainjp.com/ri-ben-chuang-ye-start-up.html"/>
        <id>https://sofiainjp.com/ri-ben-chuang-ye-start-up.html</id>
            <category term="Startup in Japan"/>

        <updated>2022-08-05T08:51:21+09:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/19/3.jpg" alt="" />
                    有關於經營管理簽證的申請，請行政書士是一個簡化很多流程的方式，但要記得找一個可信任的行政書士！除了可以跟行政書士討論自己的經營管理計畫，行政書士也會給你回饋和建議來完整你的計畫書，接著就是要將資金匯入日本，但要匯款進入日本是不容易的事情，就我淺薄的理解，你的公司要先有一個日本合夥人，並以他的名義來開立公司、銀行帳戶、租借辦公室，至於細節可能就要問行政書士了，畢竟這是他們的專業服務，找專業且有經驗的行政書士討論，不僅能在文件的準備上給予建議，也能夠協助判斷事業計畫是否可行，能夠長久經營的事業計畫是一切的前提。 設立公司本身並不困難，能否順利經營下去才是真正的難關 除了請專業行政書士協助申辦經營管理簽證外，還有另一種稱為「創業簽證」的項目。一些地方自治團體制定了外國人創業活動管理支援計劃，並得到了經濟產業省的認可，開展了以擴大吸收外國創業者和促進創業發展為目的的“外國人創業活動促進事業(創業簽證)”。申請創業簽證時，有志創業的外國企業家向下述地方自治團體提交“創業準備活動計劃書”等，該自治團體就會判斷是否符合簽證的必要條件，並向外國企業家發放確認證書。外國企業家向地方出入國在留管理局提交自治體發行的確認證書和必要檔案，如果審查結果判斷符合要求，外國企業家將被批准最長1年( 6個月後需要更新)的居留資格“特定活動”，外國企業家可為創業進行準備。外國企業進入日本後，在留期間滿足“經營管理”在留資格所需的條件後，在留資格可變更為“經營管理”，並在日本實際開展業務。 有了6個月的「創業簽證」後，就可以人到日本後再成立公司。在日本有許多地方都有自治體引進外國人創業人才的推進事業，可參考經濟產業省外国人起業活動促進事業網站。網站裡面有提供許多豐富的訊息，每個都市地區都會有所謂的「國家戰略特區促進」，例如東京都傾向的創業項目可能有「都市再生・医療・創業・雇用・女性活躍の推進等」，新瀉市也鼓勵外國人到當地創業。若有興趣可以進一步了解。 透過「創業簽證」，即便你在日本沒有合夥人也有機會進入日本創業，也就是透過繳交所需要的資料給地方政府（以新瀉市為例） 1. 創業活動確認申請書 Application for Confirmation of Business Startup Activities 2. 創業活動計画書 Plan for Business Startup Activities 3. 創業活動の工程表 Time Schedule of Business Startup Activities 4. 履歴書 Resume of the applicant 5. 誓約書 Written Pledge 6. 申請人の上陸後6月間における居住を明らかにする書類（賃貸契約書の写しなど） Documents clarifying where&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/19/3.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>有關於經營管理簽證的申請，請行政書士是一個簡化很多流程的方式，但要記得找一個可信任的行政書士！除了可以跟行政書士討論自己的經營管理計畫，行政書士也會給你回饋和建議來完整你的計畫書，接著就是要將資金匯入日本，但要匯款進入日本是不容易的事情，就我淺薄的理解，你的公司要先有一個日本合夥人，並以他的名義來開立公司、銀行帳戶、租借辦公室，至於細節可能就要問行政書士了，畢竟這是他們的專業服務，找專業且有經驗的行政書士討論，不僅能在文件的準備上給予建議，也能夠協助判斷事業計畫是否可行，能夠長久經營的事業計畫是一切的前提。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>設立公司本身並不困難，能否順利經營下去才是真正的難關</p>
</blockquote>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/19/640-creativity-concept-chalkboard-letters-of-business-plan-words.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/19/responsive/640-creativity-concept-chalkboard-letters-of-business-plan-words-xs.jpg 300w ,https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/19/responsive/640-creativity-concept-chalkboard-letters-of-business-plan-words-sm.jpg 480w ,https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/19/responsive/640-creativity-concept-chalkboard-letters-of-business-plan-words-md.jpg 768w ,https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/19/responsive/640-creativity-concept-chalkboard-letters-of-business-plan-words-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/19/responsive/640-creativity-concept-chalkboard-letters-of-business-plan-words-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/19/responsive/640-creativity-concept-chalkboard-letters-of-business-plan-words-2xl.jpg 1600w"  alt="" width="640" height="483"></figure>
<p>除了請專業行政書士協助申辦經營管理簽證外，還有另一種稱為「創業簽證」的項目。一些地方自治團體制定了外國人創業活動管理支援計劃，並得到了經濟產業省的認可，開展了以擴大吸收外國創業者和促進創業發展為目的的“外國人創業活動促進事業(創業簽證)”。申請創業簽證時，有志創業的外國企業家向下述地方自治團體提交“創業準備活動計劃書”等，該自治團體就會判斷是否符合簽證的必要條件，並向外國企業家發放確認證書。外國企業家向地方出入國在留管理局提交自治體發行的確認證書和必要檔案，如果審查結果判斷符合要求，外國企業家將被批准最長1年( 6個月後需要更新)的居留資格“特定活動”，外國企業家可為創業進行準備。外國企業進入日本後，在留期間滿足“經營管理”在留資格所需的條件後，在留資格可變更為“經營管理”，並在日本實際開展業務。</p>
<p>有了6個月的「創業簽證」後，就可以人到日本後再成立公司。在日本有許多地方都有自治體引進外國人創業人才的推進事業，可參考<a href="https://www.meti.go.jp/policy/newbusiness/startupvisa/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">經濟產業省外国人起業活動促進事業網站</a>。網站裡面有提供許多豐富的訊息，每個都市地區都會有所謂的「國家戰略特區促進」，例如<a href="https://www.investtokyo.metro.tokyo.lg.jp/jp/about/nssz/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">東京都</a>傾向的創業項目可能有「都市再生・医療・創業・雇用・女性活躍の推進等」，<a href="https://www.city.niigata.lg.jp/business/boeki/kokukei_jigyou/kokusaitokkusougyou.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">新瀉市</a>也鼓勵外國人到當地創業。若有興趣可以進一步了解。</p>
<p>透過「創業簽證」，即便你在日本沒有合夥人也有機會進入日本創業，也就是透過繳交所需要的資料給地方政府（以新瀉市為例）</p>
<p>1. 創業活動確認申請書<br>　 Application for Confirmation of Business Startup Activities<br>2. 創業活動計画書<br>　 Plan for Business Startup Activities<br>3. 創業活動の工程表<br>　 Time Schedule of Business Startup Activities<br>4. 履歴書<br>　 Resume of the applicant<br>5. 誓約書<br>　 Written Pledge<br>6. 申請人の上陸後6月間における居住を明らかにする書類（賃貸契約書の写しなど）<br>　 Documents clarifying where the applicant will be residing for 6 months after arrival in Japan<br>7. 申請人の上陸後6月間における生活資金及び帰国資金を明らかにする書類（預金の残高証明など）<br>　 Documents detailing the applicant's bank account balance<br>8. 申請人の旅券の写し<br>　 A copy of the applicant's passport (the page showing the identification details)<br>9. その他、必要書類（創業活動計画書の内容・根拠が具体的にわかるもの）<br>　 Other necessary documents</p>
<p>當地政府多能提供英文的諮詢服務，我們可以透過email進一步了解需要繳交的資料，讓我們能更完善的準備，當資料繳交完後，日本當地的相關人員就會進一步透過你的事業計畫來了解你的事業、未來營運方式、審視你的商業模式，若經審查後沒有問題，日本端就會發給「在留資格認定書」，而當獲得這份認定書後及代表你可進入日本正式設立公司。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>最困難的第一步就是獲得「在留資格認定書」</p>
</blockquote>
<p>走了第一步後，接下來就是繼續走下去～</p>
<p>--未完待續</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>日本創業 -公司設立</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sofiainjp.com/ri-ben-chuang-ye.html"/>
        <id>https://sofiainjp.com/ri-ben-chuang-ye.html</id>
            <category term="Startup in Japan"/>

        <updated>2022-08-05T08:46:34+09:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/18/1.jpg" alt="" />
                    想在日本待超過3個月時間，最重要的莫過於「簽證」。日本政府在2005年時制定了法規以利外國經營者長住日本，就是所謂的「投資經營簽證」，到了安倍政權時，更進一步放寬外國人在日本創業時的限制，也把「投資經營簽證」改名為現在的「經營管理簽證」。「經營管理簽證」就是在日本創立公司，進行經營和管理行為，就可以申請的日本中長期滯留資格的簽證。 當我人還在台灣的時候，就開始上網搜尋資料、了解申請經營管理簽證的條件。下面將之前找的資訊整理並記錄一下。 「經營管理簽證」希望申請人有實質的經營管理的行為，能夠長久穩定經營，為日本社會帶來稅收及就業機會。很多有錢人，認為在日本買房收租金做投資，就可以拿到經營管理簽證，並進一步移民日本，但事實上是，如果只是買不動產收租金進行投資，那麼就不涉及經營管理這樣的行為，不符合取得經營管理簽證的資格。 上述都是網路上找得到的茲料。但實際狀況是怎麼樣呢？ 首先是公司經營規模部分，雖然資料上提到資本額有500萬日幣就可以，但實際上，要考量你是要單獨過來還是會有家人一起過來，想當然，資本額越高是越好的，畢竟要在日本生活沒有想像中的容易，有很多稅金、保險料金要繳交呢！ 再來是事業計畫書，要把自己未來的事業好好做好一番規畫及審視，用中文完成後在請專業的翻譯人員協助翻成日文。千萬不要以為像是做一份單純的報告，這份計畫書其實是協助自己了解事業是否能在日本存活下來的重要依據，如果過去曾有創業經驗，當然很容易撰寫，但如果是菜鳥新手，有很多的細節必須要考量、思考。所有的開立公司成本（租借辦公室、網路費、水電費、電話費、聘請專業人員像的費用、產品的成本等等），以及收入是否能不赤字？這些都是透過事業計畫書可以幫助自己了解的。當然，也可以花錢請行政書士協助你，但是還是要自己先規劃過一遍才能更清楚細節不是嗎？畢竟未來要成為公司的老闆，不能不知道公司的財務及願景啊！！ 至於到底要怎麼租辦公室？要如何匯款到日本？這個雞生蛋蛋生雞的問題..... --未完待續
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/18/1.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>想在日本待超過3個月時間，最重要的莫過於「簽證」。日本政府在2005年時制定了法規以利外國經營者長住日本，就是所謂的「投資經營簽證」，到了安倍政權時，更進一步放寬外國人在日本創業時的限制，也<span class="tie-highlight tie-highlight-yellow">把「投資經營簽證」改名為現在的「經營管理簽證」。</span>「經營管理簽證」就是在日本創立公司，進行經營和管理行為，就可以申請的日本中長期滯留資格的簽證。</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/18/640-business-people-are-meeting-for-analysis-data-figures-to-plan-business-strategies-business-discussing-concept.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/18/responsive/640-business-people-are-meeting-for-analysis-data-figures-to-plan-business-strategies-business-discussing-concept-xs.jpg 300w ,https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/18/responsive/640-business-people-are-meeting-for-analysis-data-figures-to-plan-business-strategies-business-discussing-concept-sm.jpg 480w ,https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/18/responsive/640-business-people-are-meeting-for-analysis-data-figures-to-plan-business-strategies-business-discussing-concept-md.jpg 768w ,https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/18/responsive/640-business-people-are-meeting-for-analysis-data-figures-to-plan-business-strategies-business-discussing-concept-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/18/responsive/640-business-people-are-meeting-for-analysis-data-figures-to-plan-business-strategies-business-discussing-concept-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/18/responsive/640-business-people-are-meeting-for-analysis-data-figures-to-plan-business-strategies-business-discussing-concept-2xl.jpg 1600w"  alt="" width="640" height="427"></figure>
<p>當我人還在台灣的時候，就開始上網搜尋資料、了解申請經營管理簽證的條件。下面將之前找的資訊整理並記錄一下。</p>
<ol>
<li>公司經營規模：新公司的投資金額必須在<strong>500萬日幣以上</strong>，或者<strong>雇用兩名以上的全職員工。</strong>因為雇用員工除了要支付每個月的薪水外，還必須負擔員工部分社會福利(年金、保險等)的費用，所以大多數的人都選擇<span class="tie-highlight tie-highlight-yellow">投資至少500萬日幣（最少金額），而</span>初期有租借辦公室、請稅理士結帳、公司設立申請等花費開銷。重要的事是，申請經營管理簽證的本人，做的必須是「經營管理的工作」。</li>
<li>事業計畫：申請簽證時，必須向入國管理局提交公司的<strong>事業計畫書</strong>，詳述公司的業務內容、發展方向，更重要的是必須說服日本政府，事業計劃書所提出的<span class="tie-highlight tie-highlight-yellow">公司業務內容具備可行性及持續性，也就是要讓日本政府了解你有長久經營的打算及可行的商業模式。</span></li>
<li>事務所要求：有<strong>實體的獨立辦公室</strong>，共享辦公室或只是租用一個公司地址或虛擬辦公室是無法通過申請的。</li>
<li>經營權要求：申請人必須擁有公司的實質經營權。</li>
</ol>
<p>「經營管理簽證」<span class="tie-highlight tie-highlight-yellow">希望申請人有實質的經營管理的行為</span>，能夠長久穩定經營，為日本社會帶來稅收及就業機會。很多有錢人，認為在日本買房收租金做投資，就可以拿到經營管理簽證，並進一步移民日本，但事實上是，如果只是買不動產收租金進行投資，那麼就<strong>不涉及經營管理這樣的行為</strong>，不符合取得經營管理簽證的資格。</p>
<p>上述都是網路上找得到的茲料。但實際狀況是怎麼樣呢？</p>
<p>首先是公司經營規模部分，雖然資料上提到資本額有500萬日幣就可以，但實際上，要考量你是要單獨過來還是會有家人一起過來，想當然，資本額越高是越好的，畢竟要在日本生活沒有想像中的容易，有很多稅金、保險料金要繳交呢！</p>
<p>再來是事業計畫書，要把自己未來的事業好好做好一番規畫及審視，用中文完成後在請專業的翻譯人員協助翻成日文。千萬不要以為像是做一份單純的報告，這份計畫書其實是協助自己了解事業是否能在日本存活下來的重要依據，如果過去曾有創業經驗，當然很容易撰寫，但如果是菜鳥新手，有很多的細節必須要考量、思考。所有的開立公司成本（租借辦公室、網路費、水電費、電話費、聘請專業人員像的費用、產品的成本等等），以及收入是否能不赤字？這些都是透過事業計畫書可以幫助自己了解的。當然，也可以花錢請行政書士協助你，但是還是要自己先規劃過一遍才能更清楚細節不是嗎？畢竟未來要成為公司的老闆，不能不知道公司的財務及願景啊！！</p>
<p>至於到底要怎麼租辦公室？要如何匯款到日本？這個雞生蛋蛋生雞的問題.....</p>
<p>--未完待續</p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>日本創業之初</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sofiainjp.com/dao-ri-ben-chuang-ye.html"/>
        <id>https://sofiainjp.com/dao-ri-ben-chuang-ye.html</id>
            <category term="Startup in Japan"/>

        <updated>2022-08-05T08:47:21+09:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/17/travel-2-2xl.jpeg" alt="" />
                    許多人喜歡到日本旅遊，對台灣人而言，到訪日本旅遊的頻率可能是一年一次、一年兩次或更多次，但你曾想過到日本居住嗎？ 我很喜歡日本，常在忙碌工作之餘安排時間到日本看櫻花、賞楓，但假期時間總是短短的幾天，每次到日本自由行的行程也非常緊湊、想要踏訪各個景點，所以總是裝載著許多回憶和疲憊從日本回台。 曾幻想過要到日本居住而不只是旅遊，悠閒的享受及體驗當地生活、感受四季分明的變化等，但在現實生活中幾乎是個「夢想或是幻想」，沒想到在2022年、全球疫情仍未完全平息之前，我真的能搬到日本居住。 到日本居住三個月以上的方式，比較常聽到的可能是到日本求職、嫁(娶)日本人。如果你還年輕、有點存款，可以先到日本語言學校就讀，除了增進語言能力、廣結良緣外，之後也能考慮在日本找一份工作，這是一個不錯職涯及人生經歷，且能體驗長期住在日本生活的優缺點，之後再決定是否要繼續留在日本；又或者，在就讀語言學校、在日本職場工作時，幸運的認識生命中的另一半而結婚、選擇在日本生活，這兩種方式似乎都滿適合年輕人的。 我已經不是年輕人了，所以我們選擇到日本創業？（誤） 到日本創業並不是一件容易的事情，先想像一下要放棄哪些好了，可能是原本穩定且受人尊敬的工作、一間遮風避雨的房子、一台車子，還有許多實質或是抽象的東西。當想好你可能需要丟掉放下哪些事物、接受現實中機會成本的問題後，接下來就開始思考～要如何在日本生活下去，說白話點就是「如何維生」。 享受假期時到日本旅遊很容易的事情，因為只要拿薪水來付就好了，但若想在日本居住，有積蓄確實可以幫你一把、可以活下來，但光有積蓄也無法讓你在日本長期居住，因為最重要的是「簽證」（工作簽、家族滯在簽、經營管理簽證等等），如果決定要拿經營管理簽證而採取創業行動後，就要思考要做些什麼？能不能夠真的賺到錢？上述兩項還算是自己能稍微掌控的，而不能掌控的事情在未來還有很多、很多。 當體驗「很多事是自己無法掌控」這個想法後，似乎更能「感謝每一個機會與邂逅」，活得更感恩及感激～。 至於要如何到日本創業？在異地又要如何開始？ --未完待續
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sofiainjp.com/media/posts/17/travel-2-2xl.jpeg" alt="" />
                <p>許多人喜歡到日本旅遊，對台灣人而言，到訪日本旅遊的頻率可能是一年一次、一年兩次或更多次，但你曾想過到日本居住嗎？</p>
<p>我很喜歡日本，常在忙碌工作之餘安排時間到日本看櫻花、賞楓，但假期時間總是短短的幾天，每次到日本自由行的行程也非常緊湊、想要踏訪各個景點，所以總是裝載著許多回憶和疲憊從日本回台。</p>
<p>曾幻想過要到日本居住而不只是旅遊，悠閒的享受及體驗當地生活、感受四季分明的變化等，但在現實生活中幾乎是個「<span style="text-decoration: line-through;">夢想或是</span>幻想」，沒想到在2022年、全球疫情仍未完全平息之前，我真的能搬到日本居住。</p>
<p>到日本居住三個月以上的方式，比較常聽到的可能是到日本求職、嫁(娶)日本人。如果你還年輕、有點存款，可以先到日本語言學校就讀，除了增進語言能力、廣結良緣外，之後也能考慮在日本找一份工作，這是一個不錯職涯及人生經歷，且能體驗長期住在日本生活的優缺點，之後再決定是否要繼續留在日本；又或者，在就讀語言學校、在日本職場工作時，幸運的認識生命中的另一半而結婚、選擇在日本生活，這兩種方式似乎都滿適合年輕人的。</p>
<p>我已經不是年輕人了，所以我們選擇到日本創業？（誤）</p>
<p>到日本創業並不是一件容易的事情，先想像一下要放棄哪些好了，可能是原本穩定<span style="text-decoration: line-through;">且受人尊敬</span>的工作、一間遮風避雨的房子、一台車子，還有許多實質或是抽象的東西。當想好你可能需要<span style="text-decoration: line-through;">丟掉</span>放下哪些事物、接受現實中機會成本的問題後，接下來就開始思考～要如何在日本生活下去，說白話點就是「如何維生」。</p>
<p>享受假期時到日本旅遊很容易的事情，因為只要拿薪水來付就好了，但若想在日本居住，有積蓄確實可以幫你一把、可以活下來，但光有積蓄也無法讓你在日本長期居住，因為最重要的是「簽證」（工作簽、家族滯在簽、經營管理簽證等等），如果決定要拿經營管理簽證而採取創業行動後，就要思考要做些什麼？能不能夠真的賺到錢？上述兩項還算是自己能稍微掌控的，而不能掌控的事情在未來還有很多、很多。</p>
<blockquote>
<p>當體驗「很多事是自己無法掌控」這個想法後，似乎更能「感謝每一個機會與邂逅」，活得更感恩及感激～。</p>
</blockquote>
<p>至於要如何到日本創業？在異地又要如何開始？</p>
<p>--未完待續</p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
